<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>painblogr-intro_rstats</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on painblogr-intro_rstats</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Powered by: [Hugo](http://gohugo.io) &amp; [Blogdown](https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/)</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/post/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/about/</guid>
      <description>What this course is not This is not an introductory statistics course. Running a stats test is the easy part (interpreting the results of that test is a whole other thing though). The hard part of any data analysis is getting the data into shape to be explored and analysed.
 What this course is This short-course provides an introduction to data wrangling, plotting, and reproducible research practices using the statistical computing programme R and the distributed version control system git.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/post/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/about/</guid>
      <description>What this course is not This is not an introductory statistics course. Running a stats test is the easy part (interpreting the results of that test is a whole other thing though). The hard part of any data analysis is getting the data into shape to be explored and analysed.
What this course is This short-course provides an introduction to data wrangling, plotting, and reproducible research practices using the statistical computing programme R{ target=&amp;rdquo;_blank&amp;rdquo; } and the distributed version control system git{ target=&amp;rdquo;_blank&amp;rdquo; }.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/post/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/about/</guid>
      <description>What this course is not This is not an introductory statistics course. Running a stats test is the easy part (interpreting the results of that test is a whole other thing though). The hard part of any data analysis is getting the data into shape to be explored and analysed.
What this course is This short-course provides an introduction to data wrangling, plotting, and reproducible research practices using the statistical computing programme R{ target=&amp;rdquo;_blank&amp;rdquo; } and the distributed version control system git{ target=&amp;rdquo;_blank&amp;rdquo; }.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for the course</title>
      <link>/post/preparing-for-the-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/preparing-for-the-course/</guid>
      <description>Do I need any experience using R or git? The course assumes some basic knowledge of R and git. If the commands data[ , 1:5] or git commit mean absolutely nothing to you, then you need to complete one or more introductory online courses in preparation for this course (see below for some good free options), and the ‘R Programming’ course provided through the R package swirl (instructions below).
 What software must I install on my computer?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swirl</title>
      <link>/post/swirl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/swirl/</guid>
      <description>The swirl package for R was developed by the Swirl Development Team, and includes a suite of step-by-step interactive training courses on R, which are aimed primarily at the novice and intermediate user. Before starting this course you should at the very least be familiar with the content of the swirl course: ‘R Programming’. During the course, we shall also complete all or parts of the swirl courses: ‘Getting and Cleaning Data’, and ‘Exploratory Data Analysis’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free courses</title>
      <link>/post/free-courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/free-courses/</guid>
      <description>If you are a complete newbie to R and git, use these free online courses to learn the basics.
R online  Introduction to R by datacamp.com
 R Programming by codeschool.com
   git online  Try git by codeschool.com
 Learn git by codecademy.com
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheatsheets</title>
      <link>/post/cheatsheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cheatsheets/</guid>
      <description>Remembering commands can be difficult, especially when you are a new user or you are out of practise. So here are links to some useful cheat-sheets:
R / RStudio  Base R (source: Mhairi McNeill via rstudio.com)
 Importing data (source: rstudio.com)
 Data wrangling with dplyr and tidyr (source: rstudio.com)
 Data visualization with ggplot2 (source: rstudio.com)
 Regular expressions (source: Ian Kopacka via rstudio.com)
 RMarkdown cheatsheet (source: rstudio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool stuff</title>
      <link>/post/cool-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cool-stuff/</guid>
      <description>Seeing Theory A visual introduction to probability and statistics
I strongly recommend that you go play around with the interactive plots at Seeing Theory. The project was designed and created by Daniel Kunin with support from Brown University’s Royce Fellowship Program and National Science Foundation group STATS4STEM. The goal of the project is to make statistics more accessible to a wider range of students through interactive visualizations.
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>